

MEHBOOB ASLAM

Project Engineer
FREYSSINETGULF LLC
mahboob_but@yahoo.com

Mobile: 0505581337

EDUCATION

BTECH Civil Engineering, Indian Institute Of Engineer 2006

Diploma in Civil Engineer Punjab Board of Technical Education 1992

PROFESSION Civil Engineer

MEMBERSHIPS
Member of Society of
Civil Engineer UAE

LANGUAGES

- English
- Urdu/Pashtu
- Arabic

REFERENCE

- Dominic Peacock
- Fmail·

dpeacock@freyssinet.sofr.me

• Phone: +971-50-6136569

.

• Stephane Marrec Email: smarrec@freyssinet.com.ht

SUMMARY

A professional Civil Engineer having 22 years' extensive experience in post contract projects related to infrastructure, structure, roads and bridges in various emirates of UAE and with reputable international consultants. Currently working with FREYSSINET as Site Project Engineer in Roads and Infrastructure project by ETHAD RAILWAY (Abu Dhabi).

RELEVANT PROJECT EXPERIENCE

- Repair work Bridges and Building Damage Concrete by Micro concrete and Shotcrete, additional PT and TFC. Heavy lifting, bearing replacements
- Roads and Utilities, Streetscape Package 1 Masdar City- Abu Dhabi, UAE
- Damac Akoya Oxygen (Roads and Infrastructure) (IP2 IP5), Roads Infrastructure works for 1600 villas Dubai, UAE
- Reem Oasis Development Phase II Miscellaneous Infrastructure Road & Structure works by Emaar, Dubai, UAE
- Dubai Downtown Development, Dubai, UAE
- Al Watani Residential Development Phase 1A & 2 by Sorouh, Abu Dhabi, UAE
- Marina Development Roads, Infrastructure &Landscaping Works by Emaar- Umm al Quwain, UAE
- Mina Al Arabia Phase 1 Roads, Infrastructure and Bridges by RAK properties, Ras Al Khaima UAE
- Hamriyah Cloverleaf Interchanges and Infrastructure work by Hamriya Free Zone, Sharjah, UAE
- Tunnel and Bridge Structures Under the Ramps of New Airport Road and Alain Road Interchange by ADM, Abu Dhabi, UAE
- Widening of West Mussafah Road from Ip 35 To Mussafah Bridges by ADM, Abu Dhabi, UAE
- Bridge Interchange On Mip 39d on Al Ain/Abu Dhabi Road by ADM, Abu Dhabi, UAE
- Multi-Storey Underground Car Park Structure for 466 Car Spaces by ADM, Abu Dhabi, UAE
- 3rd Bridge Crossing Abu Dhabi Island C2-Bridge.
- Abu Dhabi Mall-Shopping Center
- Repair and Reinstate Accident Damaged Bridge on Gold Souq and Rotana flyovers Palm Gateway- Strengthening with Carbon Rod, Drop Cap.
- Paramount Towers Shear wall Thickening & strengthening with Foreva TFC;
- The Flying Saucer Sharjah Existing Damage Slab Repair by SHOTCETE

1

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>Senior Site Project Engineer Freyssinet Gulf L.L.C.</u> United Arab Emirates 2011 - 2022,



Supervised arid executed external and internal post tensioning activities using both C and K range systems.

Carried out weekly inspection of post tensioning equipment. Maintaining log for calibrations.

Carried out the replacement and installation of pot bearings.

Prepared project take offs, variation orders and work procedures.

Carried out friction tests to establish various coefficients in elongation calculations.

Coordinated design changes and on site changes with Clients,

Concrete columns Supporting PT slab drop cap retrofit

Method Of Strengthening R.C Slab After Deflection Using Over Lay Method Prepaid Method Statement For Friction Test AND Method Statement For Post Tensioning

Jack Lifting Bridge, change Bearing or repair

- Supervision of Post Tensioning Activities BRIDGES, PRECAST BEAM AND SILO.(Layout, Installation, Stressing & Grouting
- Jacketing of Foundations and columns by micro concrete
- Monitoring of Field Progress, Preparation of Daily Progress Reports, Weekly Progress and to keep the records in appropriate manner.
- Main Contractor and Consultant dealing.
- Concrete repair of bridge deck
- Repair methods and solutionsCommon ways to repair a slab are to surface fill or inject with epoxy or polyurethane
- Reinstatement of bearing connection
- Concrete protection works by coating:
- Structural Damage repair, Hydraulic Lifting Bearing Replacement Bridge Post tensioning
- Wide cracks in concrete are best patched and sealed with a concrete patching compound.
- Pre cast Beams. Silo Structures
- Supervision of the two types of shotcrete processes, dry shotcrete (also known as gunite), and wet shotcrete
- Shotcrete, gunite or sprayed concrete is concrete or mortar conveyed through a hose and pneumatically projected at high velocity onto a surface
 - specialize in the planning, design, construction, operation, maintenance of public infrastructures such as buildings, dams, bridges, harbors

CH2M Hill - Halcrow, Dubai, UAE 2009-2011

Assistant Resident Engineer

Reem Oasis Development by Emaar Phase II Miscellaneous Infrastructure Road , Bridges and Marina Development by Emaar, Structure works, Dubai

Total Under Controlled of 93 Towers. Total Budget of the Project: US \$: 5.00 (Million USD). Total Built-up Area: 700,500.00 sq. m.

The Commencement Date: 12/10/2006 and Still Going on. {A, B & C type Towers - G+4 Parking+25 Typical Floors +H.C}. {D type Towers - G+6 Parking+40 Typical Floors +H.C.}.

 $\{F \text{ type Towers (Shopping Mall, School's, Masjid's, Police Office, Hospital, Civil Defense Office, District Cooling Plant, Gardens, Recreation Club, Lake, Parking Areas ,Street and all types of Infrastructure and etc.) – G+7 Floor.}.$

- > Supervision for the construction of one Building (i.e. G+4) at Al Dhaid Area, Sharjah.
- > Supervision for construction more than 40 Villas (G+1)+Majlis+service block+B.wall most of their finance was by Program of Shekh Zayed for Housing at AL Falaj Area.
- > Supervision for construction of B.Wall for FEWA (Falaj Electricity and Water Authority) Power Station.
- > Follow up Consultant Instructions/Comments.
- > Follow up Municipality Rules and Regulation

Duties/Responsibilities

Entire Responsibility person for construction of Five Towers (i.e. D14, B16, B17, B22 & B23).

- > Solving Technical and Financial obligations through organizing Minutes of Meetings (MOM's) / Conferences between Client and Contractors/ Sub-Contractor's.
- Preparing required messages between Client, Main Contractor and Sub-Contractor's.
- Checking all kinds of Construction Shop Drawing Submittals.
- ➤ Daily checking and Follow-up the site construction documents with main contractor and subcontractors.
- Inspecting and approving the civil works at site.
- Responsible for material inspection upon providing at the site.
- > Checking all kinds of construction Documents and issuing Instructions / Comments.
- Issuing Site Instructions as per the site situations.
- Coordinating with all kinds' concerned suppliers.
- Coordinate with Client Representatives and Contractor Officials.
- ➤ Preparing / organizing / managing the Weekly, Frontline, Monthly, Quarterly and Half yearly Minutes of Meetings (MOM).
- > Daily follow-up the contractors & sub-contractors Daily Report (i.e. Total Site Manpower Status.)
- ➤ Daily Follow-up the concerned Site Documents (i.e. Request for Inspection and Approval (R.F.I.A), Request for Information(R.F.I), Site Instructions (S.I), Document Submittal (D.S) / Transmittals (D.T), Technical Submittal (T.S) / Transmittal (T.T), Material Submittals (M.S), Material Verification Record (M.V.R) and Materials Approval (M.A) and Non Conformation Report (N.C.R.))

Al Watani Residential Development

Site Project Engineer (Infrastructure/Structure) \ 2004-2009, UAE

Supervision and monitoring of MEP work in different ongoing projects to ensure quality of work is incompliance with approved shop drawings and specifications and get daily progress report from site supervisor, foreman and update to manager.

The project comprises construction of deep and shallow services which includes storm and sewerage networks, potable water works, combined irrigation and firefighting, reinforced concrete reservoir, pump station, road crossing duct and paving works and road construction. Whereas, the landscape works includes construction of two parks for the community,

power facilities, pollution control, facilities, water supply, and transportation systems.

Verification of the measurements of the sub-contractor's work executed.

- Check the safety of workers and other at site.
- Prepare quotation for new projects on the basis of quantity of equipment's and different size pipes measured in AutoCAD & standard rates of previous projects.
- Maintaining quality of work as per requirement of client.
- Preparing the daily and weekly progress report & manpower report.
- Construction of Military Bldgs at Maliha Military Camp-Sharjah Project MW-OU-124-2009
- Supervision of Post Tensioning Activities BRIDGES, PRECAST BEAM AND SILO.(Layout, Installation, Stressing & Grouting
- Concrete repair of bridge deck

BESIX Construction, Abu Dhabi, UAE



Site Engineer, June 1998- September 2004

- 1. Tunnel and Bridge Structures Under the Ramps of New Airport Road and Alain Road Interchange, Abu Dhabi, UAE
- 2. Widening of West Mussafah Road from Ip 35 To Mussafah Bridges, Abu Dhabi, UAE
- 3. Bridge Interchange On MIP 39d on Al Ain /Abu Dhabi Road, Abu Dhabi, UAE
- 4. Multi-Story Underground Car Park Structure for 466 Car Spaces, Abu Dhabi, UAE

Site Managements, Site Supervision, Quality control, Safety Managements, Labor Supervision, Site Surveying, Quantity surveying, Form Work & Scaffolding Supervision, Supervision of Green Concrete Placing and Compaction, Steel fixing, Flooring, Marble & Ceramic tile works, Stone cladding, Water proofing, Paint works, Curbstone & Paving, Gypsum decoration, False ceiling, Electric & Plumbing and Internal & External finishing work.

- Pursuing the work done on site as per the specifications and method of statement and checking the materials delivered on site as per approved ones.
- Supervising construction of roads, which includes preparation of sub grade (cut and fills area), sub base preparation, application of prime-coat and tack-coat, asphalt base course and wearing course and pavement markings and sign traffic posts.
- Supervised defects and maintenance in roads, which includes the milling and overlay operation over existing asphalt.
- Supervising the piling construction works for bored vertical and batter piles with permanent and temporary casing, secant piles and concreting of the same. Monitoring pile load tests, integrity testing and keeping contemporary records.
- Supervision of concrete pouring of bridge, tunnels and underground parking structure for base slabs, piers, abutments, retaining walls and deck slabs.
- Inspection of steel reinforcement placing as per approved shop drawings for bridge, tunnels and parking structure.

DECLARATION:

I hope that the above mentioned particulars meet your requirements and if given a chance to serve you , I assure you that I can do my best to carry out duties with much more interest to care for the entire satisfaction of my superior

Mehboob Aslam